Prabhat Kumar

Mobile: +91-7827320278 | Email: kmrprabhat@outlook.com



I am an experienced software developer with over 12+ years in the field and a broad understanding of engineering and software technology. I have expert knowledge in the design, development, and maintenance of product systems and subsystems. I can meet strict deadlines and effectively achieve engineering and organizational goals. Currently, I am employed as a Software developer engineer at Amazon Inc.

CAPABILITIES & SKILLS

- 12+ years of professional experience in software development engineering
- Expertise in software architecture, design patterns, and object-oriented programming
- Strong understanding of software development methodologies, such as Agile, Scrum, and Waterfall
- Proven ability to lead and manage software development projects from concept to delivery
- Expertise in developing and maintaining web and mobile applications
- Strong experience in developing and integrating RESTful APIs
- Expertise in frontend development using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and modern frameworks such as AngularJS and React
- Strong experience with back-end development using languages such as Java, Python, and NodeJS
- Proven ability to work with and integrate various databases such as MySQL, MongoDB, Redis and DynamoDB
- Strong experience with version control systems such as Git, SVN, and TFS
- Proven ability to troubleshoot and debug code, and provide effective solutions to technical problems
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills, with the ability to present technical information to both technical and non-technical audiences
- Proven ability to mentor and lead teams in software development projects.

Technical Skills – JAVA, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks – Angular 4+, React JS

Business Domain - Localization, Advertisements, Energy, logistics & e-commerce

Languages – English & Hindi.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering	2010
Electronics and communication. Birla Institute of Technology Mesra	
Sr Secondary School	2005
Science Math's. Shri Mahaveer Digambar Jain c-scheme Jaipur	
Secondary School	2003
Science. Shivaji Inter College Kanpur	

Pro Bono work and awards/recognition

Maharashtra Govt – Green building initiative, where we help assess the building rating of the existing building (15K+). With our help we saved around 10Cr+ to Govt and reduced the timeline from 12 months to 1month. Received Certificate from Honorable Minister of Road Transport and Highways (MoRTH) Sh. Nitin Jairam Gadkari, who were personally involved and praised the efforts.

Griha – Helped design a platform to assess building readiness while opening office after covid, and help the organization prepare better. All the Govt Organization are using that platform including ISRO, PWD, Indian Army and Indian Airforce and Ministries. Received written recognition from DR. Ajay Mathur (Director general International Solar Alliance & CEO Griha)

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE



Amazon Inc | SDE | BwP(Buy with Prime)

September 2022 to present

MCF provides fulfillment services for orders placed off Amazon.com, like your own website or other ecommerce sales channels. With MCF, you gain access to Amazon's world-class fulfillment network. Once your inventory is in an Amazon fulfillment center, MCF handles the picking, packing, and shipping directly to customers for orders placed on sales channels outside Amazon. Orders are fully trackable with real-time updates for packages, and tracking information is provided to you regardless of carrier.

- Developing next generation end to end customer notifications for the Supply chain portal (SCP)
- Implemented data handling solutions to the customer data

Adobe Systems India Inc | Computer Scientist | Internationalization Octo

October 2017 to September 2022

Internationalization is the process of designing a software application so that it can be adapted to various languages and regions without engineering changes. Localization is the process of adapting internationalized software for a specific region or language by adding locale-specific components and translating text.

- Developed new Adobe localization Framework toolkit to translate all Adobe Products
- Developed automatic linguistic bug creation and fix for linguistic error and generated reporting dashboard, which improved bug fixing significantly.
- Developed system for automated translation of help documents using markdown

Times Internet Ltd (Times of India Group) | Manager level II | Colombia

June 2016 to October 2017

Colombia is a smart marketing platform that allows marketers to connect with digital consumers and processing billions of requests a day and matching the right marketing offer to the right users at the right time and the right format, considers more than 1,000 separate attributes in real time. It engages with nearly 200 million digital users a month across Times Internet Ltd properties and partner publisher

- Developed self-service portal for ad serving platform.
- Create multiple types of ad methods to optimize and enhance ad consumption.
- Created additional parameters to efficient targeting.

SSN Logistics Pvt Ltd (Delhivery) | Senior Associate Technology | LMAP

November 2015 to June 2016

LMAP is decoupling the last module as a separate Product, which enables performance enhancement, Mobile approach and reducing risk. Developed webapp for LMAP(Last Mile As Product).

- Rolled out to 500+ centers and supported roll out operations.
- Handled half a million packages data and reliably integrated with third party service providers.

Wipro Technologies Ltd | Sr. Software Engineer

April 2011 to November 2015

InSite is a Data management service that can be a key enabler, allowing drilling and other relevant rig site data to be collected, transmitted, replicated, and managed in real time. The InSite service is a common platform for replicating well site data generated and acquired by Sperry. I have also managed end to end automation testing

- Developed NexGen Insite platform
- Developed first prototype of Insite Anywhere web Product